<CodeList xmlns="http://www.cdisc.org/ns/odm/v1.3" xmlns:nciodm="http://ncicb.nci.nih.gov/xml/odm/EVS/CDISC" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" OID="CL.C125747.ED2TC" Name="Expanded Disability Rating Scale - Postacute Interview Survivor Version Questionnaire Test Code" DataType="text" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C125747" nciodm:CodeListExtensible="No">
                <Description>
                    <TranslatedText xml:lang="en">Expanded Disability Rating Scale - Postacute Interview Survivor Version test code.</TranslatedText>
                </Description>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ED202_3" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C125803">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>ED2-Correct Date and Time</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Expanded Disability Rating Scale - Postacute Interview Survivor Version - Are you able to give the correct date and time within a few seconds of being asked?</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Expanded DRS-PI Survivor Version - Give Correct Date and Time When Asked</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ED204_1" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C125804">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>ED2-Feed Independently Without Help</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Expanded Disability Rating Scale - Postacute Interview Survivor Version - Can you feed yourself independently or manage tube feedings appropriately without help or reminders?</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Expanded DRS-PI Survivor Version - Feed Yourself Independently Without Help</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ED204_2" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C125805">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>ED2-Understand Feeding Utensils</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Expanded Disability Rating Scale - Postacute Interview Survivor Version - Do you understand what eating or feeding utensils or equipment are for and how they should be used?</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Expanded DRS-PI Survivor Version - Understand Feeding Utensils</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ED204_3" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C125806">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>ED2-Know Meal Times</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Expanded Disability Rating Scale - Postacute Interview Survivor Version - Do you know when meal or feeding times are?</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Expanded DRS-PI Survivor Version - Know Meal Times</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ED205_1" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C125807">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>ED2-Use Toilet Independently</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Expanded Disability Rating Scale - Postacute Interview Survivor Version - Can you use the toilet or manage your bowel and bladder routine independently and appropriately without help or reminders?</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Expanded DRS-PI Survivor Version - Use Toilet Independently</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ED205_2" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C125808">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>ED2-Manage Clothing When Toileting</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Expanded Disability Rating Scale - Postacute Interview Survivor Version - Do you understand how to manage your clothing or special equipment when toileting or in bowel and bladder management?</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Expanded DRS-PI Survivor Version - Manage Clothing When Toileting</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ED205_3" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C125809">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>ED2-Know When to Use Toilet</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Expanded Disability Rating Scale - Postacute Interview Survivor Version - Do you know when to use the toilet or to conduct bowel and bladder management?</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Expanded DRS-PI Survivor Version - Know When to Use Toilet</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ED206_1" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C125810">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>ED2-Can Dress/Groom Independently</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Expanded Disability Rating Scale - Postacute Interview Survivor Version - Can you dress and groom yourself independently and appropriately or direct someone else in these activities without help or reminders?</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Expanded DRS-PI Survivor Version - Can Dress and Groom Self Independently</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ED206_2" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C125811">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>ED2-Know How to Bathe/Wash</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Expanded Disability Rating Scale - Postacute Interview Survivor Version - Do you know how to bathe and wash?</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Expanded DRS-PI Survivor Version - Know How to Bathe and Wash</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ED206_3" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C125812">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>ED2-Understand How to Get Dressed</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Expanded Disability Rating Scale - Postacute Interview Survivor Version - Do you understand how to get dressed?</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Expanded DRS-PI Survivor Version - Understand How to Get Dressed</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ED206_4" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C125813">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>ED2-Start/Finish Grooming Activities</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Expanded Disability Rating Scale - Postacute Interview Survivor Version - Can you start and finish these grooming activities without prompting?</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Expanded DRS-PI Survivor Version - Start and Finish Grooming Activities</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ED207_1" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C125814">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>ED2-Function Completely Independently</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Expanded Disability Rating Scale - Postacute Interview Survivor Version - Do you function completely independently? That is, you do not require any physical assistance, supervision, equipment, devices, or reminders for cognitive, social, behavioral, emotional, and physical function?</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Expanded DRS-PI Survivor Version - Function Completely Independently</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ED207_2" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C125815">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>ED2-Require Specific Aids/Equipment</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Expanded Disability Rating Scale - Postacute Interview Survivor Version - Do you REQUIRE special aids or equipment, such as, a brace, walker, wheelchair, memory notebook, day planner, verbal reminders, prompts, cues, or alarm watch because of a disability?</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Expanded DRS-PI Survivor Version - Require Special Aids or Equipment</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ED207_3" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C125816">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>ED2-Require Physical Assistance</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Expanded Disability Rating Scale - Postacute Interview Survivor Version - Do you require physical assistance from another person to meet daily needs?</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Expanded DRS-PI Survivor Version - Require Physical Assistance</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ED207_4" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C125817">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>ED2-Require Assistance Thinking Tasks</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Expanded Disability Rating Scale - Postacute Interview Survivor Version - Do you require assistance from another person in tasks that require thinking abilities?</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Expanded DRS-PI Survivor Version - Require Assistance Thinking Tasks</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ED207_5" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C125818">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>ED2-Require Assistance Managing Emotions</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Expanded Disability Rating Scale - Postacute Interview Survivor Version - Do you require assistance from another person to manage emotions and behavior?</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Expanded DRS-PI Survivor Version - Require Assistance Managing Emotions</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ED207_6A" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C125819">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>ED2-Need a Helper Always Close By</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Expanded Disability Rating Scale - Postacute Interview Survivor Version - Do you take care of some of your needs but also need a helper who is always close by?</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Expanded DRS-PI Survivor Version - Need a Helper Always Close By</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ED207_6B" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C125820">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>ED2-Need Help With All Major Activities</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Expanded Disability Rating Scale - Postacute Interview Survivor Version - Do you need help with all major activities and the assistance of another person all the time?</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Expanded DRS-PI Survivor Version - Need Help With All Major Activities</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ED207_6C" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C125821">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>ED2-Need 24-Hour Care</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Expanded Disability Rating Scale - Postacute Interview Survivor Version - Do you need 24-hour care and are not able to help with your own care at all?</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Expanded DRS-PI Survivor Version - Need 24-Hour Care</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ED208_1" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C125822">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>ED2-Independent Work/Social Situations</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Expanded Disability Rating Scale - Postacute Interview Survivor Version - Can you function with complete independence in work or social situations?</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Expanded DRS-PI Survivor Version - Function With Independent Work or Social Situations</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ED208_2" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C125823">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>ED2-Understand/Follow Directions</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Expanded Disability Rating Scale - Postacute Interview Survivor Version - Can you understand, remember, and follow directions?</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Expanded DRS-PI Survivor Version - Understand and Follow Directions</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ED208_3" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C125824">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>ED2-Keep Track of Time/Schedules</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Expanded Disability Rating Scale - Postacute Interview Survivor Version - Can you keep track of time, schedules and appointments?</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Expanded DRS-PI Survivor Version - Keep Track of Time</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ED208_4" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C125825">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>ED2-Perform Jobs, Manage Home/School</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Expanded Disability Rating Scale - Postacute Interview Survivor Version - How certain are you that you can perform in a wide variety of jobs of your choosing or manage a home independently or participate in school full-time?</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Expanded DRS-PI Survivor Version - Perform Jobs or Manage a Home Independently</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ED208_5" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C125826">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>ED2-Successful With Accommodations</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Expanded Disability Rating Scale - Postacute Interview Survivor Version - How certain are you that you can be successful at work, school or in home management with some reduction in the work load or with other accommodations due to disabilities?</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Expanded DRS-PI Survivor Version - Successful With Accommodations</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ED208_6" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C125827">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>ED2-Successful With Limited Choices</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Expanded Disability Rating Scale - Postacute Interview Survivor Version - How certain are you that you can be successful at work, school or in home management but with limited choices in jobs or school courses due to disabilities?</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Expanded DRS-PI Survivor Version - Successful With Limited Choices</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ED208_7" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C125828">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>ED2-Work With Frequent Support</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Expanded Disability Rating Scale - Postacute Interview Survivor Version - How certain are you that you can be able to work at home or in a special setting like a sheltered workshop in which the work is very routine and there is very frequent supervision and support?</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Expanded DRS-PI Survivor Version - Work With Frequent Supervision and Support</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <nciodm:CDISCSubmissionValue>ED2TC</nciodm:CDISCSubmissionValue>
                <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Expanded Disability Rating Scale - Postacute Interview Survivor Version Questionnaire Test Code</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                <nciodm:PreferredTerm>CDISC Questionnaire Expanded DRS-PI Survivor Version Test Code Terminology</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
            </CodeList>
            
