<CodeList xmlns="http://www.cdisc.org/ns/odm/v1.3" xmlns:nciodm="http://ncicb.nci.nih.gov/xml/odm/EVS/CDISC" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" OID="CL.C103329.GNRLOBSC" Name="General Observation Class" DataType="text" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C103329" nciodm:CodeListExtensible="No">
                <Description>
                    <TranslatedText xml:lang="en">Terminology related to the classification of a CDISC domain.</TranslatedText>
                </Description>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ADAM OTHER" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C103375">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>An analysis dataset that doesn't conform to a pre-defined ADaM dataset structure (e.g. ADSL, BDS or OCCDS).</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>CDISC Other ADaM Dataset</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="BASIC DATA STRUCTURE" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C103371">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>BDS</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>An ADaM BDS dataset contains one or more records per subject, per analysis parameter, per analysis time point. Variables include the value being analyzed (e.g., AVAL) and the description of the value being analyzed (e.g., PARAM). Other variables in the dataset provide more information about the value being analyzed (e.g., the subject identification) or describe and trace the derivation of it (e.g., DTYPE) or support the analysis of it (e.g., treatment variables, covariates).</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>CDISC Basic Data Structure Dataset</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="EVENTS" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C103372">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>This SDTM class captures planned protocol milestones such as randomization and study completion, and occurrences, conditions, or incidents independent of planned study evaluations occurring during the trial (e.g., adverse events) or prior to the trial (e.g., medical history).</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>CDISC Events Class</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="FINDINGS" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C103373">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>This SDTM class captures the observations resulting from planned evaluations to address specific tests or questions such as laboratory tests, ECG testing, and questions listed on questionnaires.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>CDISC Findings Class</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="FINDINGS ABOUT" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C135396">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>This SDTM class is a specialization of the findings general observation class. It is intended, as its name implies, to be used when collected data represent findings about an event or intervention that cannot be represented within an event or intervention record or as a supplemental qualifier to such a record.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>CDISC Findings About Class</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="INTEGRATED BASIC DATA STRUCTURE" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C132357">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>IBDS</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>IBDS is the ADaM Model for the Integrated Basic Data Structure. The structure includes per pool as defined in the integrated SAP when multiple records per subject are included in integrated ADSL.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>CDISC Integrated Basic Data Structure Dataset</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="INTEGRATED OCCURRENCE DATA STRUCTURE" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C132358">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>IOCCDS</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>IOCCDS is the ADaM Model for Integrated Occurrence Data structure. The structure includes per pool as defined in the integrated SAP when multiple records per subject are included in integrated ADSL.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>CDISC Integrated Occurrence Data Structure Dataset</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="INTEGRATED SUBJECT LEVEL" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C132359">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>IADSL</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>IADSL is the ADaM Model for Integrated Subject Level Analysis Dataset. The structure is one record per subject per pool as defined in the integrated SAP. Multiple records per subject are required in an integrated ADSL dataset when any subject's data is used in more than one pool and the values for subject-level variables differ across pools.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>CDISC Integrated Subject Level Dataset</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="INTERVENTIONS" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C103374">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>This SDTM class captures investigational, therapeutic and other treatments that are administered to the subject (with some actual or expected physiological effect) either as specified by the study protocol (e.g., exposure to study drug), coincident with the study assessment period (e.g., concomitant medications), or self-administered by the subject (such as use of alcohol, tobacco, or caffeine).</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>CDISC Interventions Class</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="OCCURRENCE DATA STRUCTURE" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C123454">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>OCCDS</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>The Occurrence Data Structure (OCCDS) is the ADaM data structure for occurrence analysis. Occurrence analysis is the counting of subjects with a record or term, and often includes a structured hierarchy of dictionary coding categories.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>CDISC Occurrence Data Structure</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="RELATIONSHIP" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C103376">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>This SDTM class provides a means to link related records between datasets. It includes the RELREC and SUPPQUAL datasets.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>CDISC Relationship Class</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="SPECIAL PURPOSE" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C103377">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>This SDTM class contains a set of domains which do not conform to the Findings, Events or Interventions observation classes. The domains included are DM, CO, SE and SV.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>CDISC Special Purpose Class</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="STUDY REFERENCE" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C147271">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>This special purpose SDTM class contains further descriptions of study-specific identifiers that will be used in subject based domains.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>CDISC Study Reference Class</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="SUBJECT LEVEL ANALYSIS DATASET" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C103378">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>ADSL</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>The Subject-Level Analysis Dataset (ADSL) is a one-record-per-subject dataset which contains variables that describe subject demographic characteristics and group the subjects for analysis. ADSL is the primary source for subject-level variables included in other analysis datasets such as population flags and treatment variables.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>CDISC Subject Level Analysis Dataset</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="TRIAL DESIGN" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C103379">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>This SDTM class describes the plan for the procedures to be followed in a clinical trial, including planned and actual timing of events, control group, method of allocating treatments, blinding methods, assignment of epochs that subjects pass through in the course of a trial.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>CDISC Trial Design Class</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <nciodm:CDISCSubmissionValue>GNRLOBSC</nciodm:CDISCSubmissionValue>
                <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>General Observation Class</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                <nciodm:PreferredTerm>CDISC SDTM General Observation Class Terminology</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
            </CodeList>
            
