<CodeList xmlns="http://www.cdisc.org/ns/odm/v1.3" xmlns:nciodm="http://ncicb.nci.nih.gov/xml/odm/EVS/CDISC" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" OID="CL.C85492.METHOD" Name="Method" DataType="text" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C85492" nciodm:CodeListExtensible="Yes">
                <Description>
                    <TranslatedText xml:lang="en">Method is any technique or procedure (an action) that determines how an observation or clinical finding was made.</TranslatedText>
                </Description>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ACID FAST STAIN" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C23015">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A microscopy staining method used to examine a specimen for the presence of acid-fast microorganisms, specifically mycobacteria.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Acid Fast Bacillae Staining Method</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ACRIDINE ORANGE STAIN" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C85554">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A microscopy staining method that utilizes acridine orange, a fluorescent cationic dye that is selective for nucleic acids, to determine the presence of viable cells or microorganisms in a sample. Acridine orange interacts with RNA and DNA and the lysosomal compartment of cells.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Acridine Orange Staining Method</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="AGAR DILUTION" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C85555">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A method to determine microbial susceptibility to antibiotics in which test bacteria is inoculated onto agar plates with serial dilutions of know quantities of antibiotics. The minimum inhibitory concentration of antibiotic is assessed.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Agar Dilution Method</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="AHG-ENHANCED COMPLEMENT-DEPENDENT LYMPHOCYTOTOXICITY ASSAY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C130170">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A form of complement-dependent lymphocytotoxicity assay with the addition of anti-human globulin (AHG) which is a complement fixing antibody to human immunoglobulin. AHG binds to both complement proteins and non-complement-fixing antibodies.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>AHG-enhanced Complement-dependent Lymphocytotoxicity Assay</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ALCIAN BLUE AND PERIODIC ACID SCHIFF STAIN" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C92304">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A microscopy staining method that utilizes periodic acid, an oxoacid of iodine, Schiff reagent, the reaction product of fuchsine and sodium bisulfite, and Alcian blue, a water soluble copper phthalocyanine dye. This staining method is used to differentially stain glycoproteins.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Alcian Blue and Periodic Acid Schiff Staining Method</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ALCIAN BLUE STAIN" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C92299">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A microscopy staining method that utilizes alcian blue, a cationic, water soluble copper-containing phthalocyanine dye to determine the presence of acid mucopolysaccharides and glycosaminoglycans.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Alcian Blue Staining Method</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="AMSLER GRID" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C123464">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A diagrammatic method to test visual acuity and presence of macular degeneration, which uses a uniform square grid of lines with a dot in the center.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Amsler Grid</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ANALYTICAL ULTRACENTRIFUGATION" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C120681">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A high-speed centrifugation-based method that uses an optical detection system to monitor and record data during the centrifugation process.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Analytical Ultracentrifugation</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ANGIOGRAPHY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C20080">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A method used to create an image of blood vessels.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Angiography</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ANTIBIOTIC AGAR SCREEN" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C85557">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A method used to detect organisms that have resistance to a single concentration of antibiotics in an agar matrix.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Antibiotic Agar Screening Method</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ANTIMICROBIAL COMBINATION TESTING" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C85558">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A method to determine the microbial susceptibility to two or more antibiotics. Numerical result translated into indifference, antagonism, synergism, or additive.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Antimicrobial Combination Testing Method</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="APPLANATION TONOMETRY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C120682">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A method in which a constant pressure is applied to the surface of the cornea in order to flatten a prespecified area of the membrane, which is used to calculate intraocular pressure.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Applanation Tonometry</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ARTERIAL SPIN LABELING FUNCTIONAL MRI" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C116450">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>ASL fMRI</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A noninvasive fMRI technique that uses arterial water as an endogenous tracer to measure cerebral blood flow by magnetically labeling the proton spins of the arterial water prior to reaching the imaged volume.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Arterial Spin Labeling Magnetic Resonance Imaging</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ATOMIC ABSORPTION SPECTROMETRY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C85574">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A spectrometric method that determines the type and concentration of metal elements in a sample, based upon the principle that each elemental metal absorbs a particular wavelength of ultraviolet light when exposed to heat.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Atomic Absorption Spectroscopy</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="AUDIOMETRY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C38036">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Testing conducted utilizing a manual or microprocessor audiometer to test for hearing loss.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Audiometric Test</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="AURAMINE STAIN" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C102599">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Auramine O</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A microscopy acid fast staining method that utilizes auramine O, a bright yellow ketonimine dye, which binds to the mycolic acid in the cell walls of acid fast microorganisms.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Auramine Staining Method</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="AUSCULTATION" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C85573">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Listening with a device, such as a stethoscope, to anatomical locations that produce audible sounds like the heart, lungs and abdomen.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Auscultation</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="BAC ACGH" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C116157">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>BAC Array-based CGH</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Bacterial Artificial Chromosome Array-based CGH</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Bacterial Artificial Chromosome Array-based Comparative Genomic Hybridization</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A molecular cytogenetic method combining chromosomal comparative genomic hybridization technique and microarray to detect chromosomal aberrations and changes in DNA copy numbers, using bacterial artificial chromosome clones containing target DNA fragments for hybridization.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Bacterial Artificial Chromosome Array-based Comparative Genomic Hybridization</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="BETA LACTAMASE" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C85576">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A test that detects beta lactamase produced by Staphylococcus species, Haemophilus species, Moraxella catarrhalis, and Neisseria gonorrhoeae.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Beta Lactamase Screening Method</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="BIOPSY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C15189">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>The removal of tissue specimens or fluid from the living body for microscopic examination, performed to establish a diagnosis.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Biopsy</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="CALCOFLUOR WHITE STAIN" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C85577">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A microscopy staining method that utilizes calcofluor, a fluorescent dye that preferentially stains chitin and cellulose on the cell walls of fungi, parasites, and some cysts of the Pneumocystis genus.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Calcofluor White Staining Method</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="CALCULATION" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C54125">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>The procedure or activity of determining a result by mathematical or logical methods. (NCI)</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Calculation</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="CAPILLARY ELECTROPHORESIS" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C17637">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>An electrophoresis procedure, in which a sample is introduced into a capillary tube and the components are separated by the application of high voltage. (NCI)</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Capillary Electrophoresis</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="CELLULOSE TAPE" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C85578">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A microbiological technique for specimen collection and mounting for microscopic examination that utilizes a cellulose-based adhesive ribbon.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Cellulose Tape Method</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="CENTRIFUGATION" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C16410">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A separation technique used to isolate substances of different densities based on centrifugal force.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Centrifugation</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="CHROMATOGRAPHY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C16431">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A technique for the separation of complex mixtures that relies on the differential affinities of substances for a gas or liquid mobile medium and for a stationary adsorbing medium through which they pass.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Chromatography</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="CINEANGIOGRAPHY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C127679">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A type of angiography in which motion picture camera technology is used to record the passage of dye (usually fluorescent) through blood vessels and the heart.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Cineangiography</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="CISH" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C40960">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Chromogenic in Situ Hybridization</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A laboratory procedure that combines the sequence-specific detection aspects of FISH with the simple detection methods of immunohistochemistry. Briefly, sequence-specific probes are hybridized to cells fixed on slides and the sequestered probe is visualized by a peroxidase reaction. It has the advantage of being a less costly assay that does not require fluorescence microscopy with results that are stable over time.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Chromogenic In Situ Hybridization</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="CLINICAL EVALUATION" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C124351">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>An appraisal of a patient's condition by a clinician that is based on a physical exam, medical history, patient's account of symptoms, laboratory assessments, and/or imaging analysis.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Clinical Evaluation</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="CLIP" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C111163">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Cross-Linking and Immunoprecipitation</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A type of immunoprecipitation protocol that employs UV-light induced covalent cross-linking of molecules (for instance protein and RNA) prior to the immunoprecipitation and purification steps.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Cross-Linking and Immunoprecipitation</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="CLIP SEQUENCING" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C116152">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>CLIP-Seq</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Cross-linking Immunoprecipitation High-throughput Sequencing</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>HITS-CLIP</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A molecular biology method combining crosslinking-immunoprecipitation and high-throughput sequencing techniques to detect and map RNA-protein interactions.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Cross-linking Immunoprecipitation High-throughput Sequencing</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="CLOT DETECTION" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C111095">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Any of several methods used to detect the presence of or quantify the formation of a thrombus in a specimen. (NCI)</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Clot Detection</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="COLORIMETRY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C111096">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A method to measure the absorbance of visible wavelengths of light using a colorimeter.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Colorimetry</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="COMPLEMENT-DEPENDENT LYMPHOCYTOTOXICITY ASSAY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C130171">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A method that detects the presence and reaction of complement-fixing alloantibodies to donor lymphocytes, via the addition of complement proteins and lysis of the lymphocytes.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Complement-dependent Lymphocytotoxicity Assay</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="CONTACT SPECULAR MICROSCOPY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C120683">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A type of specular microscopy in which the specular microscope makes contact with the cornea of the eye.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Contact Specular Microscopy</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="CONTRAST ENHANCED MRI" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C46087">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A technique that uses radiofrequency waves and a magnet to image the body. The images are enhanced by the addition of contrast agents which selectively intensify anatomical regions to intensify the clarity of the image for diagnostic purposes. (NCI)</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Contrast-enhanced Magnetic Resonance Imaging</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="CORONARY ANGIOGRAPHY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C100085">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A procedure in which the catheter is passed into the aortic root or other great vessels for the purpose of angiography of the native coronary arteries or bypass grafts supplying native coronary arteries.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Coronary Angiography</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="CRYOSCOPY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C122162">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A method for measuring the molar concentration of a substance in solution by determining the freezing point of the solution.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Cryoscopy</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="CT SCAN" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C17204">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>CT</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Computed Tomography</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>An imaging technique for examining structures within the body by scanning them with X rays and using a computer to construct a series of cross-sectional scans along a single axis.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Computed Tomography</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="CYSTOSCOPY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C16482">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Endoscopic examination of the urinary bladder or urethra.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Cystoscopy</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="DARK FIELD MICROSCOPY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C85837">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A microscopic technique in which the light that does not come into contact with the structure or details of interest is subtracted from the ocular image. This yields an image in which the structure or details are alight while the areas where the structures or details are absent are dark.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Dark Field Microscopy</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="DIGITAL PCR ARRAY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C116158">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Digital PCR</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Digital Polymerase Chain Reaction</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>dPCR</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A technique used to deliver high-throughput digital PCR. The digital array partitions a sample premixed with PCR reagents into hundreds of individual PCR reactions, which allows the absolute quantification of target sequences and rare allele detection, as compared to conventional real-time quantitative PCR.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Digital Array</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="DIPSTICK" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C106516">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A strip of composite material that is coated or impregnated with reagents designed to detect the presence of an analyte in a liquid by producing a color change.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Dipstick</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="DIRECT SEQUENCING" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C116154">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A technique used to identify the sequence of individual nucleotides in a single strand of DNA fragment template which does not require subcloning and can be a plasmid insert, genomic DNA or a PCR product.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Direct Sequencing</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="DISK DIFFUSION" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C85595">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A method to determine microbial susceptibility to antibiotics in which filter paper disks containing known concentrations of antibiotics are placed on the agar surface that has been previously inoculated with the bacteria of interest. Microbial susceptibility is assessed by measuring the area around the disk that is free of microbial growth.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Disk Diffusion Method</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="DNA MICROARRAY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C18158">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>DNA Chip</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Gene Chip</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Gene Expression Array</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>An orderly array of DNA samples affixed to a support. The chip is used in various types of hybridization experiments. Used when a more specific microarray methodology is not specified.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>DNA Microarray Chip</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="DUCTOGRAPHY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C123465">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Galactography</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A type of mammography that uses contrast medium to visualize the ducts of the breast.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Ductography</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="DUKE INCISION METHOD" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C122163">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A method for assessing bleeding time in which a controlled incision is made on the ear or fingertip.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Duke Incision Method</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="DXA SCAN" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C48789">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A technique for scanning bone and measuring bone mineral density (BMD).</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Dual X-ray Absorptiometry</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="DYNAMIC CONTRAST ENHANCED MRI" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C62665">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A type of contrast-enhanced MRI that allows observation of functional properties in addition to structural properties.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Dynamic Contrast-Enhanced Magnetic Resonance Imaging</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="DYNAMIC LIGHT SCATTERING" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C62329">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Photon Correlation Spectroscopy</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Quasi-elastic Light Scattering</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A type of spectroscopy that utilizes a laser beam to irradiate a sample containing particles in suspension, resulting in light scattering.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Photon Correlation Spectroscopy</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ECHOCARDIOGRAPHY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C16525">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A procedure that uses high-frequency sound waves (ultrasound) to create an image of the heart.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Echocardiography</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="EEG" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C38054">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>ELECTROENCEPHALOGRAPHY</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A technique used to capture and record spontaneous electrical activity of the brain by the application of electrodes to the scalp.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Electroencephalography</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="EIA" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C17455">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Enzyme Immunoassay</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Any of several immunoassay methods that use an enzyme covalently linked to an antigen or antibody as a label; the most common types are enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay (ELISA) and enzyme-multiplied immunoassay technique (EMIT).</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Enzyme Immunoassay</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ELASTOGRAPHY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C106517">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>An ultrasound-based imaging technique used to examine the stiffness or elasticity of a tissue by applying mechanical compression or vibration to the tissue being imaged. (NCI)</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Elastography</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ELECTROCHEMILUMINESCENCE" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C111193">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A method in which electromagnetic radiation, in the form of light emission, is generated from an electrochemical reaction in a solution. (NCI)</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Electrochemiluminescence</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ELECTROCHEMILUMINESCENCE IMMUNOASSAY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C111194">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A method in which electromagnetic radiation, in the form of light emission, is generated from an electrochemical reaction in a solution due to the formation of antigen-antibody complexes.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Electrochemiluminescence Immunoassay</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ELECTROMYOGRAPHY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C38056">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A method to assess skeletal muscle function and nerve control, obtained by recording and studying the intrinsic electrical properties of the muscles.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Electromyography</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ELECTROPHORESIS" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C16536">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>The motion of charged particles in a colloid under the influence of an electric field; particles with a positive charge go to the cathode and negative to the anode.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Electrophoresis</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ELISA" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C16553">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Enzyme-linked Immunosorbent Assay</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>An immunoassay for detecting and measuring antigens or antibodies in a solution; the solution is run over a surface to which immobilized antibodies specific to the substance have been attached, and if the substance is present, it will bind to the antibody layer, and its presence is verified and visualized with an application of antibodies that have been tagged in some way.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>ELISA</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ELISPOT" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C102632">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Enzyme-linked Immunosorbent Spot Assay</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A highly sensitive immunoassay capable of detecting secreted materials from individuals cells upon activation. If the material of interest is secreted in response to a particular stimulus, then the material will bind to a specific immobilized antibody. Binding is then verified and visualized by applying other antibodies that have been tagged in some way.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Enzyme-linked Immunosorbent Spot Assay</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ENDOSCOPY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C16546">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>An examination of the body using an endoscope.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Endoscopic Procedure</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ENDPOINT DILUTION ASSAY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C120684">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>An in vitro cell based assay in which plated host cells are inoculated with serial dilutions of an infective agent and observed for cytotoxic effects in order to calculate the titer.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Endpoint Dilution Assay</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ENZYMATIC COLORIMETRY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C111195">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A type of colorimetry that makes use of an enzymatic reaction to induce a color change. (NCI)</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Enzymatic Colorimetry</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ENZYMATIC ULTRACENTRIFUGATION" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C122164">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A high-speed centrifugation-based method that uses enzymatic catalytic reaction to quantify a substance.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Enzymatic Ultracentrifugation</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ENZYME MULTIPLIED IMMUNOASSAY TECHNIQUE" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C111196">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>EMIT</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A type of homogenous immunoassay in which sample is applied to a reagent mixture of enzyme-labeled ligand, antibody, and substrate. Substrate binding to enzyme leads to inactivation and unlabeled-ligand in the sample can be quantified by colorimetric analysis.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Enzyme Multiplied Immunoassay Technique</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="EPSILOMETER" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C85596">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A method to determine microbial susceptibility to antibiotics in which a plastic strip impregnated with the antibiotic of interest is placed on an agar plate that has been inoculated with bacteria. The antibiotic diffuses from the strip producing a concentration gradient of drug on the agar. The point at which the elliptical shaped area of growth inhibition meets the strip is the minimum inhibitory concentration of the drug of interest.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Epsilometry</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ETDRS EYE CHART" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C117877">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A diagrammatic method to test visual acuity which incorporates the Bailey-Lovie layout in conjunction with Sloan optotypes.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Early Treatment of Diabetic Retinopathy Study Eye Chart</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="FARNSWORTH-MUNSELL 100 HUE TEST" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C130172">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A diagrammatic method to test color blindness or deficiencies, which uses 100 colors from the Munsell color system arranged in rows of four color families and containing 25 hues for each color. The subject must put the hues in order based on the anchor colors on the ends of each row.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Farnsworth-Munsell 100 Hue Test</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="FISH" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C17563">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Fluorescence in Situ Hybridization</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A physical mapping approach that uses fluorescent tags to detect hybridization of probes within metaphase chromosomes or less condensed somatic interphase chromatin. This technique can be used for identification of chromosomal abnormalities and for gene mapping.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Fluorescence In Situ Hybridization</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="FLAME PHOTOMETRY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C106523">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A type of atomic spectroscopy that qualitatively or quantitatively measures select cations (particularly Na, K, Rb, Cs, Ca, Ba, Cu) by utilizing a low temperature flame capable of exciting a valence electron to an upper energy state which emits light at a wavelength unique to each cation as the electron returns to its ground state. (NCI)</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Flame Photometry</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="FLOW CYTOMETRY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C16585">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A technique for counting, examining or sorting microscopic particles suspended in a stream of fluid. The cells are placed in a fluid (with or without light-sensitive dye) and passed in a stream before a laser or other type of light.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Flow Cytometry</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="FLOW MICROSCOPY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C112284">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A method of measuring the number of cells in a sample by placing the cells in a fluid and passing them, in a stream, through a special light microscope that can record and analyze images of the cells to determine the presence of foreign particles, cell counts, protein aggregates and morphology information.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Flow Microscopy</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="FLUORESCENT IMMUNOASSAY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C17370">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Fluorescent Antibody Assay</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Immunofluorescence Assay</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A bioassay in which fluorescent-coupled antibodies or antigens are used to quantify or qualify a biological response to a stimulus.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Fluorescent Antibody Procedure</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="FLUORESCENT MICROSCOPY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C16856">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Microscopy of specimens stained with fluorescent dye (usually fluorescein isothiocyanate) or of naturally fluorescent materials, which emit light when exposed to ultraviolet or blue light.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Fluorescence Microscopy</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="FLUORESCENT SPOT TEST" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C132427">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A&#160;method to assess enzymatic activity in which a&#160;substrate reagent&#160;is incubated with a biological specimen and spotted on filter paper. The spots are then examined for fluorescence, which&#160;correlates with&#160;enzyme activity.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Fluorescent Spot Test</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="FLUORIMETRY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C62322">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>An analytical method that utilizes ultraviolet light to excite the sample and detects the fluorescence emitted during the return of the sample to its ground state. (NCI)</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Fluorimetry</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="FORCED OSCILLATION TECHNIQUE" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C122165">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>FOT</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A non-invasive method to evaluate respiratory mechanical properties of the lung and airways using small-amplitude pressure oscillations superimposed on the normal, tidal breathing of a subject.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Forced Oscillation Technique</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="FUNCTIONAL MRI" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C17958">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>fMRI</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A type of MRI that takes a series of images of an organ in quick succession and statistically analyzes the differences between the images.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Functional Magnetic Resonance Imaging</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="GC/MS" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C111203">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Gas Chromatography/Mass Spectrometry</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>An analytical technique where gas chromatography is coupled with mass spectrometry in order to separate, identify, and quantify substances in a sample. (NCI)</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Gas Chromatography Mass Spectrometry</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="GC/MS-CI" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C120686">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>An analytical technique where gas chromatography is coupled with chemical ionization mass spectrometry in order to separate, identify, and quantify substances in a sample.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Gas Chromatography/Chemical Ionization Mass Spectrometry</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="GC/MS-EI" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C120687">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>An analytical technique where gas chromatography is coupled with electron ionization mass spectrometry in order to separate, identify, and quantify substances in a sample.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Gas Chromatography/Electron Ionization Mass Spectrometry</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="GC/MS/MS" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C120685">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>An analytical technique where gas chromatography is coupled to tandem mass spectrometry in order to separate, identify, and quantify substances in a sample.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Gas Chromatography/Tandem Mass Spectrometry</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="GEL ELECTROPHORESIS" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C18091">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A method of separating large molecules (such as DNA fragments or proteins) from a mixture of similar molecules by electrophoretic filtration through a gelatinous matrix.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Gel Electrophoresis</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="GIEMSA STAIN" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C85598">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A microscopy staining method that utilizes Giemsa, a mixture of ethylene blue and eosin, which forms purplish-black crystals when dried. This stain preferentially binds to the phosphate groups of DNA and aggregates at areas with an increase in adenine-thymine binding, thus leading to chromosomal staining patterns that lend themselves to g-banding analysis. Additionally Giemsa can be used as a differential stain to determine microbial cell adherence to human cells as well as in the diagnosis of malaria, spirochete, and protozoal infections.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Giemsa Staining Method</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="GRADIENT DIFFUSION" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C85599">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A method to determine microbial susceptibility to antibiotics in which an agar plate, which has a concentration gradient of the drug within the agar, is streaked with the microorganism of interest. Microbial susceptibility as well as minimum inhibitory concentration of antibiotic is assessed.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Gradient Diffusion Method</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="GRAM STAIN" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C23014">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A microscopy staining method for staining and identifying bacteria, based on the differential retention of a crystal violet-iodine complex within the cell membrane. Gram-positive organisms will appear blue-black or purple while Gram-negative organisms will appear red.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Gram Staining Method</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="HANSEL STAIN" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C111205">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A microscopy staining method that uses Hansel reagent to differentiate eosinophils and neutrophils in a specimen. (NCI)</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Hansel Staining Method</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="HEMAGGLUTINATION ASSAY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C130173">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>An in vitro assay that is used to determine the relative concentration of viruses, bacteria, or antibodies in which serial dilutions of solution containing virus, bacteria, or antibody are applied to red blood cells in culture to look for the presence of hemagglutination.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Hemagglutination Assay</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="HEMAGGLUTINATION INHIBITION ASSAY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C120688">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>An in vitro assay that is used to determine whether antibodies present in serum samples will inhibit hemagglutination in a cell culture plate containing red blood cells and a hemagglutinating agent.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Hemagglutination Inhibition Assay</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="HEMATOXYLIN AND EOSIN STAIN" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C23011">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>H&amp;E Stain</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A microscopy staining method that utilizes two separate dyes, one staining the nucleus and the other staining the cytoplasm and connective tissue. Hematoxylin is a dark purplish dye that stains the chromatin (nuclear material) within the nucleus. Eosin is an orangish-pink to red dye that stains the cytoplasmic material including connective tissue and collagen.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Hematoxylin and Eosin Staining Method</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="HEMOCYTOMETRY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C120689">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A method that uses a thick glass slide containing a chamber with a defined volume, which is etched with a precisely ruled grid and is used to quantify cells or cell-sized particles in suspension.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Hemocytometry</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="HEPATITIS C VIRUS RECOMBINANT IMMUNOBLOT ASSAY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C95525">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>An assay used to verify the presence of anti-HCV antibodies in a blood sample. Serum is incubated with a membrane strip on which four recombinant viral proteins are attached. The immunoblot is considered positive if two or more proteins react, and indeterminate if only one positive band is detected. (NCI)</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Hepatitis C Virus Recombinant Immunoblot Assay</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="HIGH LEVEL AMINOGLYCOSIDE SCREEN" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C85556">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A method to determine microbial susceptibility to high concentrations of aminoglycoside antibiotics.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Aminoglycoside Screening Method</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="HIGH RESOLUTION MELT ANALYSIS" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C130174">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A reverse real-time polymerase chain reaction technique in which fluorescently labeled double-stranded DNA is slowly melted apart by increasing temperature.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>High Resolution Melt Analysis</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="HILLMEN COLOR CHART" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C132428">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A visual color scale created by Hillman et al in 2004 to&#160;enable standardization of&#160;urine color in the assessment of hemoglobinuria.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Hillmen Color Chart</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="HPLC" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C16434">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>High Performance Liquid Chromatography</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Frequently referred to simply as HPLC, this form of column chromatography is used frequently in biochemistry. The analyte is forced through a column by liquid at high pressure, which decreases the time the separated components remain on the stationary phase. Less time on the column then translates to narrower peaks in the resulting chromatogram and thence to better selectivity and sensitivity.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>High Performance Liquid Chromatography</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="HPLC-FL" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C120692">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>An analytical technique where high performance liquid chromatography with a fluorescence detector is used to separate, identify, and quantify substances in a sample.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>High-performance Liquid Chromatography-Fluorescence</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="HPLC-UV" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C120693">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>An analytical technique where high performance liquid chromatography with an ultraviolet light detector is used to separate, identify, and quantify substances in a sample.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>High-performance Liquid Chromatography-UV</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="HPLC/IEX" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C120690">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>An analytical technique where high performance liquid chromatography is coupled to ion exchange chromatography in order to separate proteins based on net charge.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>High-performance Liquid Chromatography/Ion-Exchange Chromatography</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="HPLC/MS" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C103513">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>High Performance Liquid Chromatography/Mass Spectrometry</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>An analytical technique wherein high performance liquid chromatography is coupled to mass spectrometry in order to separate, identify, and quantify substances in a sample.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>High Performance Liquid Chromatography Mass Spectrometry</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="HPLC/MS/MS" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C120691">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>An analytical technique where high performance liquid chromatography is coupled to tandem mass spectrometry in order to separate, identify, and quantify substances in a sample.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>High-performance Liquid Chromatography/Tandem Mass Spectrometry</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ICP-MS" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C62328">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A mass spectrometry technique that uses inductively-coupled plasma generated from argon gas to atomize and ionize a sample. The resulting ions are separated and analyzed using a mass spectrometer.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Inductively-Coupled Plasma Mass Spectrometry</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="IHC" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C23020">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Immunohistochemistry</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Immunohistochemical staining techniques allow for the visualization of antigens via the sequential application of a specific antibody to the antigen (primary antibody), a secondary antibody to the primary antibody and an enzyme complex with a chromogenic substrate. The enzymatic activation of the chromogen results in a visible reaction product at the antigen site. The specimen may then be counterstained and coverslipped. Results are interpreted using a light microscope and aid in the differential diagnosis of pathophysiological processes, which may or may not be associated with a particular antigen.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Immunohistochemistry Staining Method</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="IMMUNOASSAY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C16714">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>An immunological procedure involving the usage of enzyme-antibody or enzyme-antigen conjugates, antienzyme antibodies, or enzyme-antienzyme complexes.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Immunoenzyme Procedure</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="IMMUNOBLOT" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C17638">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A technique for analyzing or identifying proteins immobilized on a filter by complementary reaction with specific antibodies. (NCI)</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Immunoblot Analysis</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="IMMUNOCHEMILUMINOMETRIC ASSAY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C111235">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Chemiluminesence Immunoassay</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>ICMA</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>An immunoassay in which the antigen-antibody complex is quantified using light emission, which is generated from a chemical reaction.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Immunochemiluminometric Assay</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="IMMUNOPRECIPITATION" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C16724">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Antigen aggregation with antibody, in the right ratios, to cause precipitation. (NCI)</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Immunoprecipitation</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="IMMUNORADIOMETRIC ASSAY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C111236">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>IRMA</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>An antibody-excess, non-competition radioimmunometric assay in which ligand is sandwiched between an immobilized antibody on a solid phase and a radiolabeled antibody raised against a different epitope of the ligand.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Immunoradiometric Assay</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="IMMUNOTURBIDIMETRY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C106536">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A method that measures the absorbance of light from a sample which is used for quantifying an amount of analyte based on the level of turbidity produced by the formation and precipitation of an immune complex containing the analyte. (NCI)</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Immunoturbidimetry</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="IMPULSE OSCILLOMETRY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C122166">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>IOS</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A non-invasive method to measure pulmonary resistance and reactance, and the impedance of the respiratory system, using small pressure oscillation of a regular square wave of pressure 5 times per second.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Impulse Oscillometry</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="IN SITU HYBRIDIZATION" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C17562">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Use of a DNA or RNA probe to detect the presence of complementary sequences in chromosomes, cells, or tissues. (NCI)</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>In Situ Hybridization</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="INCISION-INDUCED BLEEDING METHOD" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C122039">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A method for assessing bleeding time in which a controlled incision is made in the dermis and the time to bleeding cessation is measured.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Incision-induced Bleeding Method</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="INDIA INK STAIN" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C85642">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A microscopy staining method that utilizes India Ink, a water soluble carbon-based black ink, to determine the presence of microorganisms that are surrounded by a gelatinous capsule. This is a negative staining method in which background is stained in black and the microbes and microscopic structures of interest remain white.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>India Ink Staining Method</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="INFRARED SPECTROMETRY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C85643">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A spectrometric method that determines the type and concentration of elements or chemicals in a sample, based upon the principle that the atoms in a sample will vibrate or rotate at a specific frequency when exposed to infrared light.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Infrared Spectrometry</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="INTERRUPTER TECHNIQUE" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C124352">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>RINT</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A non-invasive method of measuring airway resistance during which the subject breathes normally while airflow is interrupted at a predetermined rate and volume during the early exhalation phase.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Interrupter Technique</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="INTRAVASCULAR ULTRASOUND" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C99535">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>IVUS</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>An invasive procedure in which sound waves (called ultrasound) are bounced off of vascular tissues from within the vessel and the echoes produce a picture (sonogram).</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Intravascular Ultrasound</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="IODINE STAIN" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C85649">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A microscopy staining method that utilizes Iodine, an element belonging to the halogen group, which specifically stains polysaccharides such as cellulose, chitin, glycogen, and starch a blue color.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Iodine Staining Method</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="IRON HEMATOXYLIN STAIN" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C85650">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A microscopy staining method that utilizes a mixture of iron and hematoxylin to visualize intracellular structures in a microscopic sample. In this dye system, iron acts as a mordant to hematoxylin rendering it insoluble, thereby allowing irreversible blue-black colored dyeing to the cell nucleus.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Iron Hematoxylin Staining Method</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ISHIHARA COLOR PLATES" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C123466">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A diagrammatic method to test color blindness or deficiencies, which uses a circular form composed of multiple size circles in varying colors. A number or symbol is present in the middle and is composed of similar sized circles, which are a different color from those of the outer circular form.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Ishihara Color Plates</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="IVY INCISION METHOD" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C122167">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A method for assessing bleeding time in which a controlled incision is made on the underside of the arm and blood is drawn off of the incision site with blotting paper every 30 seconds until bleeding stops.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Ivy Incision Method</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="JAEGER EYE CHART" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C130175">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A diagrammatic method to test visual acuity that uses paragraphs of text in differing font sizes to assess near vision.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Jaeger Eye Chart</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="JAFFE REACTION" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C120694">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A colorimetric method used to measure creatinine, in which color change is directly related to the amount of creatinine in an alkaline solution containing picric acid.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Jaffe Reaction</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="KARYOTYPING" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C16768">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>The preparation, analysis, and interpretation of a karyotype, the representation of the chromosome set of a cell sample.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Karyotyping</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="KINETIC MICROPARTICLE IMMUNOASSAY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C111240">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A type of immunoassay in which the antigen of interest found in a biological specimen competes with a lattice of antigen-antibody complexes. Competing antigen inhibits lattice formation and decreases absorbance in proportion to the amount of antigen present in a biological specimen. (NCI)</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Kinetic Microparticle Immunoassay</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="KINYOUN STAIN" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C85651">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A microscopy acid fast staining method that utilizes kinyoun carbol fuchsin, a dye containing basic fuchsin in solution with ethyl alcohol and aqueous phenol. This acid fast staining technique does not require heating during the primary staining step involving the carbol fuchsin.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Kinyoun Staining Method</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="LASER CAPTURE MICRODISSECTION" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C19263">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>LCM</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>LMD</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Laser Microdissection</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A technique used for the highly specific and selective capture and isolation of a cell population from a heterogeneous tissue section, cytological preparation, or live cell culture. This technique uses direct visualization of the cells via microscopy as well as a laser energy source for cutting and extraction of the cells.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Laser Capture Microdissection</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="LC-FL" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C122169">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>An analytical technique where liquid chromatography with a fluorescence detector is used to separate, identify, and quantify substances in a sample.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Liquid Chromatography-Fluorescence</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="LC/MS" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C18475">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Liquid Chromatography/Mass Spectrometry</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>An analytical technique wherein liquid chromatography is coupled to mass spectrometry in order to separate, identify, and quantify substances in a sample.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Liquid Chromatography Mass Spectrometry</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="LC/MS/MS" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C122168">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>An analytical technique where liquid chromatography is coupled to tandem mass spectrometry in order to separate, identify, and quantify substances in a sample.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Liquid Chromatography/Tandem Mass Spectrometry</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="LEAD CITRATE STAIN" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C92301">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A microscopy staining method that utilizes lead citrate, a mixture of lead nitrate and sodium citrate, and has applications for electron microscopy staining.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Lead Citrate Staining Method</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="LIGHT MICROSCOPY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C17995">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Light microscopy is a technique for producing visible images of structures or details which are too small to be otherwise seen by the human eye. It involves passing light transmitted through or reflected from the subject through a series of lenses to be detected directly by the eye, imaged on a photographic plate, or captured digitally.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Light Microscopy</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="LIGHT SCATTERING SPECTROSCOPY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C20059">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>LiSSP</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A type of spectroscopy that measures power spectral density of surface morphology by exploiting the tendency of light to disperse into a range of directions as a result of physical interaction.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Light-Scattering Spectroscopy</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="LINE PROBE ASSAY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C102656">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>LPA</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>LiPA</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A microbial identification technique in which polymerase chain reaction is used to amplify specific nucleic acid sequences in a biospecimen. The product of this reaction is then applied to a nitrocellulose test strip containing complementary DNA probes.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Line Probe Assay</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="LIQUID SCINTILLATION COUNTING" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C122170">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A method for measuring the amount of ionizing radiation in a liquid substance. Samples are mixed with a mixture of solvent, surfactant and scintillators that can convert beta particles into light energy, which can be measured.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Liquid Scintillation Counting</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="LOOP-MEDIATED ISOTHERMAL AMPLIFICATION" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C102661">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>LAMP</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A type of nucleic acid amplification test in which sample DNA is exposed to a single temperature in the presence of multiple sets of primers and a polymerase with replication and high strand displacement activity. This test negates the need for thermal cyclers and may be a low cost alternative to PCR.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Loop-mediated Isothermal Amplification</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="LUXOL FAST BLUE AND CRESYL VIOLET STAIN" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C92300">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A microscopy staining method that utilizes luxol fast blue, an alcohol soluble copper phthalocyanine dye, and cresyl violet, an organic compound that is commonly used as a counter stain, to determine the presence of myelin as well as helicobacter and campylobacter bacterial species.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Luxol Fast Blue and Cresyl Violet Staining Method</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="MACRO BROTH DILUTION" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C85697">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A method to determine the minimum inhibitory concentration (MIC) of antibiotics in which growth media is pipetted into a test tube. Each tube contains a known concentration of drug and is inoculated with a known quantity of bacteria. The tubes are incubated for a specified period of time and each is assessed for bacterial cell growth. The drug concentration in the first tube showing no growth is known as the MIC for that antibiotic.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Macro Broth Dilution Method</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="MALDI" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C48040">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Matrix-Assisted Laser Desorption Ionization Mass Spectrometry</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A mass spectrometric technique that is used for the analysis of large biomolecules. Analyte molecules are embedded in an excess matrix of small organic molecules that show a high resonant absorption at the laser wavelength used. The matrix absorbs the laser energy, thus inducing a soft disintegration of the sample- matrix mixture into free (gas phase) matrix and analyte molecules and molecular ions. In general, only molecular ions of the analyte molecules are produced and almost no fragmentation occurs. This makes the method well suited for molecular weight determinations and mixture analysis. (CHI)</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Matrix-Assisted Laser Desorption Ionization Mass Spectrometry</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="MALDI-TOF" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C19935">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Matrix-Assisted Laser Desorption/Ionization-Time of Flight Mass Spectrometry</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>In MALDI-TOF, a laser pulse is fired into a protein or peptide sample contained in a light-absorbing matrix. A small explosion vaporizes and ionizes the sample. In the presence of a high electric field, peptide ions are accelerated down an evacuated flight tube. Because large particles travel more slowly than small ones, the masses of the ionized particles are determined by measuring their arrival time at the end of the tube.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Matrix-Assisted Laser Desorption/Ionization-Time of Flight Mass Spectrometry</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="MAMMOGRAPHY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C16818">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A type of radiography used specifically to examine breast tissue. The procedure utilizes a low-dose of x-rays or radiation to generate an image.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Mammography</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="MANUAL CLOT DETECTION" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C111245">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A clot detection method that uses a manual means (visual discernment) to detect the presence and/or quantify the formation of a thrombus in a specimen. (NCI)</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Manual Clot Detection</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="MAPH" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C116159">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Multiplex Amplifiable Probe Hybridization</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A screening method used to determine changes in complex genomes. This method uses unique short probes which are quantitatively recovered and amplified after hybridization to genomic DNA.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Multiplex Amplifiable Probe Hybridization</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="MASS SPECTROMETRY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C17156">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>MassSpec</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>An analytical technique wherein ions are separated according to their ratio of charge to mass. From the mass spectrum produced, the atomic weight of the particle can be deduced.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Mass Spectrometry</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="MECHANICAL CLOT DETECTION" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C111249">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A clot detection method that uses a mechanical means (electromagnetic mechanical or electromechanical) to detect the presence of or quantify the formation of a thrombus in a specimen. (NCI)</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Mechanical Clot Detection</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="MICRO BROTH DILUTION" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C85701">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A method to determine the minimum inhibitory concentration (MIC) of antibiotics in which growth media is pipetted into a multi-well plate. Each well contains a known concentration of drug which is inoculated with a known quantity of bacteria. The plate is incubated for a specified period of time and each well is assessed for bacterial cell growth. The drug concentration in the first well showing no growth is known as the MIC for that antibiotic.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Micro Broth Dilution Method</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="MICROARRAY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C44282">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A piece of glass or plastic on which different samples have been affixed at separate locations in an ordered manner thus forming a microscopic array. The samples are usually DNA fragments but may also be antibodies, other proteins, or tissues.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Microarray</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="MICROBIAL BIOCHEMICAL IDENTIFICATION" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C51955">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Any of a number of biochemical tests performed to identify the genus and/or species of a microorganism. These may include the assessment of gram reaction or metabolic characteristics.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Bacterial Typing Procedure</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="MICROBIAL CONCENTRATION" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C85702">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Any technique in which a sample is condensed in order to afford greater sensitivity for the detection of microorganisms.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Microbial Concentration Method</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="MICROBIAL CULTURE" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C25300">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Culture Procedure</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Any method for growing microorganisms.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Microbial Culture Procedure</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="MICROBIAL CULTURE, LIQUID" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C102668">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A method for growing microorganisms in liquid culture media.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Microbial Liquid Culture</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="MICROBIAL CULTURE, SOLID" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C102669">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A method for growing microorganisms in solid culture media.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Microbial Solid Culture</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="MICRONEUTRALIZATION ASSAY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C120695">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>An in vitro assay that is used to determine whether antibodies that can block viral infection are present in a biological specimen.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Microneutralization Assay</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="MICROPARTICLE ENZYME IMMUNOASSAY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C111252">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>MEIA</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>An enzyme immunoassay that uses antigen-coated microparticles as a substrate for antibody binding.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Microparticle Enzyme Immunoassay</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="MICROSCOPY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C16853">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>The application of microscope magnification to the study of materials that cannot be properly seen by the unaided eye. (NCI)</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Microscopy</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="MODIFIED ACID FAST STAIN" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C85736">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A microscopy staining method, that does not utilize heat in the slide preparation, used to examine a specimen for the presence of acid-fast microorganisms, specifically nocardia.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Modified Acid Fast Staining Method</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="MRI" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C16809">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Magnetic Resonance Imaging</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Imaging that uses radiofrequency waves and a strong magnetic field rather than x-rays to provide amazingly clear and detailed pictures of internal organs and tissues. The technique is valuable for the diagnosis of many pathologic conditions, including cancer, heart and vascular disease, stroke, and joint and musculoskeletal disorders.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Magnetic Resonance Imaging</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="MRI WITHOUT CONTRAST" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C114184">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A technique that uses radiofrequency waves and a magnet to image the body, in which the images are not enhanced by the addition of contrast agents.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>MRI Without Contrast</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="MRS" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C29934">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Magnetic Resonance Spectroscopy</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Magnetic resonance spectroscopy is a noninvasive imaging technique that operates by exciting and recording signals from a range of magnetic resonance frequencies, allowing the identification and quantification of several biologically significant molecules containing proton groups that resonate in the appropriate frequency range. The technique facilitates observation of the spatial distribution of metabolic patterns over a region of interest and surrounding tissue at a high spatial resolution. (NCI)</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Magnetic Resonance Spectroscopic Imaging</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="MUGA" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C38073">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Radionuclide Ventriculogram Scan</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A multi-gated acquisition (MUGA) scan and a form of radionuclide imaging that provides a comprehensive look at blood flow and the function of the lower chambers of the heart ventricles. (NCI)</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Radionuclide Ventriculogram Scan</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="MULTI-SLICE SPIRAL CT" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C106545">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A type of spiral computed tomography that employs multiple rows of detectors, each capable of producing a simultaneous image (slice). (NCI)</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Multi-slice Spiral Computed Tomography</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="MULTIPLE BREATH WASHOUT" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C130176">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A test of lung function in which changes in exhaled tracer gas concentration is analyzed for a specified number of tidal expirations, a defined period of time, or a defined index of expired gas volume.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Multiple Breath Washout</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="MULTIPLE-COMPLETE-DIGEST RESTRICTION FRAGMENT MAPPING" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C116160">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Multiple Complete Digestion</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A DNA mapping technique based on complete restriction enzyme digestion of a set of overlapping clones that provides highly redundant coverage of the mapping target.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Multiple Complete Digest Restriction Fragment Mapping</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="MULTIPLEX LIGATION-DEPENDENT PROBE AMPLIFICATION" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C116161">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>MLPA</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A type of high-throughput, multiplex PCR method that uses a single pair of PCR primers to amplify multiple targets and to determine changes in complex genomes.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Multiplex Ligation-dependent Probe Amplification</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="NEPHELOMETRY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C111281">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A method to quantify the concentration of particulate matter suspended in a liquid or gas using a nephelometer.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Nephelometry</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="NEURAMINIDASE INHIBITION ASSAY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C120696">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A type of enzyme-based assay that assesses neuraminidase activity in the presence of an enzyme inhibitor.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Neuraminidase Inhibition Assay</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="NEXT GENERATION SEQUENCING" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C101293">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Massively Parallel Sequencing</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Technologies that facilitate the rapid determination of the DNA sequence of large numbers of strands or segments of DNA, using spatially separated, clonally amplified DNA templates or molecules in a flow cell.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Next Generation Sequencing</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="NEXT GENERATION TARGETED SEQUENCING" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C130177">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A type of next generation sequencing in which specific genes or portions of genes are targeted for sequencing using amplicon-based workflow.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Next Generation Targeted Sequencing</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="NON-CONTACT SPECULAR MICROSCOPY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C120697">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A type of specular microscopy in which the specular microscope does not make contact with the cornea of the eye.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Non-Contact Specular Microscopy</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="NUCLEAR MAGNETIC RESONANCE SPECTROSCOPY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C16810">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A type of spectroscopy that detects and measures the resonant spectra of molecular species in a tissue or sample.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Magnetic Resonance Spectroscopy</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="NUCLEAR RADIOLOGY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C127514">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Any type of imaging method that uses radioactive materials.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Nuclear Radiology Imaging Procedure</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="NUCLEIC ACID AMPLIFICATION TEST" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C20055">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>NAAT</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Any of a number of molecular biological techniques that are used to copy nucleic acid sequences within a specimen, leading to an increase in the number of copies of that sequence of interest. These techniques may be used for detection of a particular gene or microorganism of interest.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Nucleic Acid Amplification Test</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="NUCLEIC ACID HYBRIDIZATION" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C16924">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A method in which single stranded nucleic acids are allowed to interact so that complexes, or hybrids, are formed by molecules with sufficiently similar, complementary sequences. By this means the degree of sequence identity can be assessed and specific sequences detected. (From Biology-online)</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Nucleic Acid Hybridization</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="NUCLEIC ACID SEQUENCING" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C18881">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>The process of determining the sequence of purines and pyrimidines in nucleic acids and polynucleotides.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Nucleic Acid Sequencing</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="OBSERVATION" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C25598">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Watching something and taking note of what happens.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Observation</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="OLIGO ACGH" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C116156">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Oligonucleotide Array-based CGH</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Oligonucleotide Array-based Comparative Genomic Hybridization</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A molecular cytogenetic method combining chromosomal comparative genomic hybridization technique and microarray to detect chromosomal aberrations and changes in DNA copy numbers in the genome, using oligonucleotides as targets for hybridization.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Oligonucleotide Array-based Comparative Genomic Hybridization</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="OPHTHALMOSCOPY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C120698">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A technique used to examine the fundus and other anatomical structures of the eye with a magnifying instrument.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Ophthalmoscopy</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="OPTICAL COHERENCE TOMOGRAPHY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C20828">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Optical Coherence Tomography (OCT) combines the principles of ultrasound with the imaging performance of a microscope. OCT uses infrared light waves that reflect off the internal microstructure within the biological tissues. The frequencies and bandwidths of infrared light are orders of magnitude higher than medical ultrasound signals, resulting in greatly increased image resolution, 8-25 times greater than any existing modality. In addition to providing high-level resolutions for the evaluation of microanatomic structures OCT is also able to provide information regarding tissue composition. (NCI)</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Optical Coherence Tomography</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="OPTICAL DENSITY MEASUREMENT" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C85776">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A quantification of the amount of light that is absorbed by or transmitted through a substance.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Optical Density Measurement</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="OPTICAL MAPPING" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C116162">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Optical Map</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A technique used for constructing the ordered and high-resolution genome or chromosome sized restriction enzyme map of an organism from a single, stained DNA molecule, digested by the restriction enzyme and imaged by an optical microscope.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Optical Mapping</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="PALPATION" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C16950">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A method of feeling with the hands during a physical examination. The health care provider touches and feels the patient's body to examine the size, consistency, texture, location and tenderness of an organ or body part.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Palpation</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="PANENDOSCOPY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C94528">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>An endoscopic examination of the pharynx, larynx, trachea and esophagus.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Panendoscopy</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="PAP STAIN" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C128984">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Papanicolau Stain</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A microscopy staining method that utilizes a mixture of dyes including hematoxylin, orange G (OG), and eosin azure, which contains variable portions of Eosin Y, light green SF yellowish, and Bismarck brown Y. This multichromatic staining method is used to differentially stain samples containing mixed cell populations.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Papanicolaou Staining Method</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="PARTICLE-ENHANCED NEPHELOMETRIC IMMUNOASSAY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C125952">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>PENIA</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A method to quantify the concentration of immunoaggregates suspended in a liquid or gas using a nephelometer. The immunoaggregates are target antigens agglutinated to antigen-specific antibody-coated polystyrene latex-enhanced particles.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Particle-Enhanced Nephelometric Immunoassay</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="PARTICLE-ENHANCED TURBIDIMETRIC IMMUNOASSAY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C125953">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>PETIA</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A method to quantify the opaqueness of a liquid using a turbidimeter, by measuring the decrease in light intensity due to the scattering effect of suspended immunoaggregates in a liquid sample. The immunoaggregates are target antigens agglutinated to antigen-specific antibody-coated polystyrene latex-enhanced particles.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Particle-Enhanced Turbidimetric Immunoassay</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="PEAK FLOWMETRY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C122171">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A method for measuring the flow of air through the bronchi upon expiration.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Peak Flowmetry</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="PELLI-ROBSON EYE CHART" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C117878">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A diagrammatic method to test visual acuity and contrast sensitivity, which uses large letters (at a 20/60 acuity) that decrease in contrast from right to left and top to bottom.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Pelli-Robson Contrast Sensitivity Eye Chart</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="PERCUSSION" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C62298">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A diagnostic test performed on a tooth by tapping on the crown with a dental instrument.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Dental Percussion</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="PERIODIC ACID SCHIFF STAIN" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C23019">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A microscopy staining method that utilizes Schiff's reagent, a solution composed of pararosanilin treated with sulfurous acid, which selectively reacts with and stains aldehydes pink to determine the presence of glycogen, mucin, mucoprotein, glycoprotein, as well as fungi. Periodic Acid Schiff staining is useful for outlining tissue structures such as basement membranes, capsules and blood vessels.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Periodic Acid Schiff Staining Method</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="PERIPHERAL ANGIOGRAPHY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C117879">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A procedure in which the catheter is passed into a peripheral vessel (usually in the groin) for the purpose of angiography of the abdomen, hands, arms, feet and legs.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Peripheral Angiography</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="PET SCAN" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C17007">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>An imaging technique for measuring the gamma radiation produced by collisions of electrons and positrons (anti-electrons) within living tissue. In positron emission tomography (PET), a subject is given a dose of a positron-emitting radionuclide attached to a metabolically active substance. A scanner reveals the tissue location of the metabolically-active substance administered.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Positron Emission Tomography</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="PET/CT SCAN" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C103512">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>An imaging technique that utilizes positron emission tomography and computed tomography in a single machine.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Positron Emission Tomography and Computed Tomography Scan</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="PET/MRI SCAN" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C103514">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>An imaging technique that utilizes positron emission tomography and magnetic resonance imaging in a single machine.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Positron Emission Tomography and Magnetic Resonance Imaging</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="PET/SPECT SCAN" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C111297">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>An imaging technique that utilizes positron emission tomography and single-photon emission computed tomography in a single machine.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Positron Emission Tomography and Single Photon Emission Computed Tomography Scan</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="PH METER" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C122172">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>An electronic device used to measure the alkalinity or acidity of a liquid or semi-solid substance.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>pH Meter</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="PHASE CONTRAST MICROSCOPY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C16857">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A microscopic technique in which the amplitude shift that occurs when light passes through a specimen highlights structures or details within the specimen.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Phase-Contrast Microscopy</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="PHENOTYPIC MULTIPLE ANTIGEN BEAD-BASED MULTIPLEX ASSAY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C130178">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A type of solid-phase multiplex assay that uses microbeads coated with recombinant or purified antigens that will identify multiple antibodies.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Phenotypic Multiple Antigen Bead-based Multiplex Assay</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="PHOROPTER" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C120699">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>An instrument composed of multiple lenses that refract the light going into the subject's eye, allowing the examiner to determine the refractive error of the eye.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Phoropter</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="PHOTOGRAPHY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C94527">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>The process by which an image is acquired by recording light emissions.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Photography</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="PHOTOMETRIC CLOT DETECTION" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C111291">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A clot detection method that uses a photometric means (measuring the absorbancy of monochromatic light) to detect the presence and/or quantify the formation of a thrombus in a specimen. (NCI)</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Photometric Clot Detection</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="PHOTOMETRY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C65109">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Measurement of the properties of light, especially luminous intensity. (NCI)</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Photometry</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="PHYSICAL EXAMINATION" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C20989">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Physical Exam</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A systemic evaluation of the body and its functions using visual inspection, palpation, percussion and auscultation. The purpose is to determine the presence or absence of physical signs of disease or abnormality for an individual's health assessment.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Physical Examination</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="PLETHYSMOGRAPHY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C122173">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Body Box</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A method used to measure changes in volume, pressure and resistance within an organ or whole body by means of a plethysmograph.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Plethysmography</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="POLYMERASE CHAIN REACTION" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C17003">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>PCR</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A method for amplifying a DNA base sequence using multiple rounds of heat denaturation of the DNA and annealing of oligonucleotide primers complementary to flanking regions in the presence of a heat-stable polymerase. This results in duplication of the targeted DNA region. Newly synthesized DNA strands can subsequently serve as additional templates for the same primer sequences, so that successive rounds of primer annealing, strand elongation, and dissociation produce rapid and highly specific amplification of the desired sequence. PCR also can be used to detect the existence of the defined sequence in a DNA sample.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Polymerase Chain Reaction</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="POLYSOMNOGRAPHY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C114185">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>PSG</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A group of tests taken during sleep to capture and record brain wave changes, eye movements, breathing rate, blood pressure, heart rate, and the electrical activity of the heart and other muscles.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Polysomnography</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="PULSE OXIMETRY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C38085">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A non-invasive method that provides estimates of arterial hemoglobin oxygen saturation by utilizing selected wavelengths of light.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Pulse Oximetry</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="PUPILLOMETRY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C120700">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A technique used to measure the diameter of a single pupil in response to stimuli.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Monocular Pupillometry</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="PYROSEQUENCING" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C99481">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A DNA sequencing technique that is based on the detection of released pyrophosphate during DNA synthesis.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Pyrosequencing</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="QUANTITATIVE CORONARY ANGIOGRAPHY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C120701">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A type of angiographic procedure that allows for direct quantitative assessment of the native coronary arteries or bypass grafts supplying native coronary arteries.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Quantitative Coronary Angiography</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="QUANTITATIVE PERIPHERAL ANGIOGRAPHY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C120702">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A type of angiographic procedure that allows for direct quantitative assessment of the vessels of the hands, arms, feet and legs.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Quantitative Peripheral Angiography</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="QUANTITATIVE REVERSE TRANSCRIPTASE POLYMERASE CHAIN REACTION" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C28408">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>qRT-PCR</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A modified polymerase chain reaction (PCR) technique in which RNA sequences are reverse transcribed into complementary DNA (cDNA) transcripts by the enzyme reverse transcriptase. The cDNA is then amplified by a PCR reaction and quantified by comparing to a standard, using fluorescent probes.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Quantitative Reverse Transcriptase PCR</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="RADIAL IMMUNODIFFUSION" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C119296">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A quantitative technique used to detect and estimate the concentration of an antigen by measuring the diameter of the ring of precipitation (precipitin ring) which is formed as a result of the interaction of the antigen and an antibody at optimal concentration. (NCI)</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Radial Immunodiffusion</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="RADIOGRAPHY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C128940">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Radiographic Exam</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A radiographic procedure using the emission of penetrating energy waves to form an image of the structure.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Radiographic Examination</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="REAL-TIME POLYMERASE CHAIN REACTION ASSAY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C51962">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Quantitative PCR</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Real Time-PCR</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>qPCR</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A modified polymerase chain reaction (PCR) technique in which DNA amplification is detected and quantified as the PCR reaction progresses, through the use of fluorescent DNA probes in the reaction mixture.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Real Time PCR</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="REBOUND TONOMETRY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C120703">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A method in which a probe is bounced off of the surface of the cornea, creating an induction current that is used to calculate intraocular pressure.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Rebound Tonometry</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="REFLECTANCE SPECTROSCOPY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C19340">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>The spectroscopic analysis of light reflected from a polished sample.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Reflectance or Transmission Spectroscopy</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="REFRACTOMETRY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C111304">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A method to measure the refractive index (propensity for light to bend) of a sample. (NCI)</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Refractometry</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="REPRESENTATIONAL OLIGONUCLEOTIDE MICROARRAY ANALYSIS" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C40211">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>ROMA</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A genomic microarray-based method that analyzes two restriction enzyme digested full genomes to identify regions in the genome that have undergone large scale variation.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Representational Oligonucleotide Microarray Analysis</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="REVERSE TRANSCRIPTASE PCR" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C18136">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>RT-PCR</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Reverse Transcription Polymerase Chain Reaction</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A molecular biology technique used to recreate and amplify complimentary DNA (cDNA) from total RNA or messenger RNA (mRNA).</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Reverse Transcriptase-Polymerase Chain Reaction</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="RIA" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C17057">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Radioimmunoassay</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Radioimmunoassay (RIA) is an immunological technique, which quantitatively determines antigen and antibody concentrations, using a radioactively labeled substance (radioligand), either directly or indirectly.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Radioimmunoassay</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="RYAN BLUE STAIN" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C85801">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A microscopy staining method that utilizes a modified trichrome stain to determine the presence of microspordial, sporulating species. This staining technique substitutes aniline blue for the fast green counterstain of the original trichrome staining method and decreased levels of phosphotungstic acid in the reagent.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Ryan Blue Staining Method</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="SANGER SEQUENCING" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C19641">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A DNA sequencing technique in which a mixture of deoxynucleosidetriphosphates (dNTPs) and chain-terminating dNTPs (which are radioactively or fluorescently labeled) are combined within the reaction mixture. Once the polymerase chain reaction is complete the DNA strands are separated by size and the labeled chain terminating dNTPs can be read in sequence by the investigator or a machine.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Dideoxy Chain Termination DNA Sequencing</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="SCANNING ELECTRON MICROSCOPY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C16855">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>An electron microscopy imaging technique that is utilized to examine structural components of a sample by passing electrons through a specimen that has been coated with a heavy metal.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Scanning Electron Microscopy</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="SCINTIGRAPHY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C62667">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>An imaging technique that uses a small dose of a radioactive chemical (isotope) called a tracer that can detect sites of cancer growth, trauma, infection or degenerative disorders. The tracer, which is either injected into a vein or swallowed, travels through the bloodstream to the target organ, and emits gamma rays, which are detected by a gamma camera and analyzed by a computer to form an image of the target organ. (NCI)</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Radionuclide Imaging</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="SEQUENCE SPECIFIC PRIMER POLYMERASE CHAIN REACTION" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C130179">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>PCR-SSP</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A modified polymerase chain reaction (PCR) technique in which primer pair(s) are used to select a highly specific nucleotide sequence of interest, which will be the only sequence amplified.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Allele Specific Primer Polymerase Chain Reaction</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="SEQUENCE-BASED TYPING POLYMERASE CHAIN REACTION" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C130180">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>SBT</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A method that uses PCR amplification of specific nucleotides to produce templates and primers that are used to provide the entirety of the nucleotide sequence of a specific DNA strand, allowing for reliable and thorough genotyping of the allele in question.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Sequence-based Typing</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="SEQUENCE-SPECIFIC OLIGONUCLEOTIDE PROBE POLYMERASE CHAIN REACTION" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C130181">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>PCR-SSOP</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A modified polymerase chain reaction (PCR) technique that uses distinct probes, specifically synthesized according to the polymorphic region of the gene of interest, to detect nucleotide differences during genotype testing.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Sequence-specific Oligonucleotide Probe Polymerase Chain Reaction</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="SEQUENCING" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C116155">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A process to identify and determine the primary structure of, and the order of constituents in a biopolymer. Used when a more specific sequencing methodology is not specified.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Biopolymer Sequencing</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="SINGLE ANTIGEN BEAD-BASED MULTIPLEX ASSAY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C130182">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A type of solid-phase multiplex assay that uses microbeads coated with a recombinant or purified antigen that will identify a single antibody.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Single Antigen Bead-based Multiplex Assay</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="SINGLE-SLICE SPIRAL CT" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C106567">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A type of spiral computed tomography that employs only one detector and produces one image (slice). (NCI)</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Single-slice Spiral Computed Tomography</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="SINGLE-STRAND CONFORMATION POLYMERASE CHAIN REACTION" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C130183">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>PCR-SSCP</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A modified polymerase chain reaction (PCR) technique followed by electrophoresis such that DNA molecular weights and three-dimensional structures are used to identify mutations.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Single-strand Conformation Polymerase Chain Reaction</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="SIZE EXCLUSION CHROMATOGRAPHY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C16433">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Gel permeation or sieve chromatography that is performed on porous gels that separate solutes on the basis of size.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Gel Filtration Chromatography</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="SLIT LAMP" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C75583">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>Examination of the anterior segment of the eye using a medical instrument called a slit lamp.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Slit-lamp Examination</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="SLOAN LETTER EYE CHART 1.25%" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C117880">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A diagrammatic method to test visual acuity that uses the Sloan optotypes and a 1.25% contrast level.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Sloan Letter Eye Chart 1.25 Percent</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="SLOAN LETTER EYE CHART 2.5%" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C117881">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A diagrammatic method to test visual acuity that uses the Sloan optotypes and a 2.5% contrast level.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Sloan Letter Eye Chart 2.5 Percent</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="SMEAR" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C65126">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>The action of spreading a thin layer of material across a surface.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Smear</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="SNELLEN EYE CHART" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C123467">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A diagrammatic method to test visual acuity, which uses a chart containing 11 lines of Sloan optotypes in varying sizes with the largest located at the top of the chart and decreasing in size toward the bottom of the chart.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Snellen Eye Chart</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="SNP ARRAY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C116151">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Genotype Chip</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>SNP Genotyping</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>SNP Probe</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Single Nucleotide Polymorphism Array</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A genomic microarray-based method able to detect single nucleotide polymorphisms.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Single Nucleotide Polymorphism Array</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="SPECT SCAN" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C17203">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A type of tomography in which gamma photon-emitting radionuclides are administered to the patient and then detected by one or more gamma cameras rotated around the patient. From the series of two-dimensional images produced, a three-dimensional image can be created by computer reconstruction.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Single Photon Emission Computed Tomography</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="SPECTROPHOTOMETRY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C116701">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A technique used to calculate the transmittance of light through a material.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Spectrophotometry</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="SPECULAR MICROSCOPY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C120542">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A noninvasive photographic technique used to visualize and examine the corneal endothelium, in which a source of light is projected onto the cornea and the subsequent image reflected from the optical interface between the corneal endothelium and the aqueous humor is captured.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Specular Microscopy</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="SPIRAL CT" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C20645">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Spiral Computed Tomography</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A method of examining body organs by scanning them with X rays and using a computer to construct a series of cross-sectional scans along a single axis.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Spiral CT</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="SPIROMETRY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C85397">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A method used to measure the breathing capacity of the lung by means of a spirometer.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Spirometry</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="STRESS ECHOCARDIOGRAPHY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C80407">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>An echocardiographic technique in which an image of the heart is produced by ultrasonography under conditions (e.g., exercise, pharmacologic agents or pacing) intended to elicit signs and symptoms of myocardial ischemia.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Stress Echocardiography</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="TEMPLATE INCISION METHOD" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C122174">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A method for assessing bleeding time in which two controlled incisions are made on the forearm using a template to guide placement of the scalpel or blade.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Template Incision Method</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="TEST STRIP" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C50322">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A piece of chemically treated medium designed to react in the presence of specific amounts of a trigger substance.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Test Strip Device Component</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="THICK SMEAR" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C85819">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A blood smear technique used to make a thick blood smear on a microscope slide which is generally used to look for blood parasites such as those causing malaria.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Thick Smear Technique</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="THIN SMEAR" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C85820">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A blood smear technique used to make a thin blood smear on a microscope slide which is generally used to look for blood parasites such as those causing malaria.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Thin Smear Technique</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="TOLUIDINE BLUE STAIN" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C92302">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A microscopy staining method that utilizes toluidine blue, a solution composed of tolonium chloride, to determine the presence of mast cells, lignin, proteoglycans and glycosaminoglycans.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Toluidine Blue Staining Method</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="TOTAL BODY IRRADIATION" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C15350">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A therapeutic procedure that involves the irradiation of the whole body with ionizing or non-ionizing radiation. (NCI)</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Total-Body Irradiation</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="TOTAL BODY RADIOGRAPHY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C96640">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A diagnostic radiologic test that involves the examination of the entire body in a single procedure.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Total Body Radiography</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="TRANSCRIPTION-MEDIATED AMPLIFICATION" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C122175">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A technique used to selectively replicate nucleic acid sequences from RNA templates using reverse transcriptase and RNA polymerase.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Transcription-mediated Amplification</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="TRANSESOPHAGEAL ECHOCARDIOGRAPHY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C80405">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>TEE</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A cardiac ultrasound performed by passing a specialized probe containing a transducer into the patient's esophagus.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Transesophageal Echocardiography</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="TRANSMISSION ELECTRON MICROSCOPY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C18216">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>An electron microscopy imaging technique that is utilized to examine structural components of a sample by passing electrons through the specimen.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Transmission Electron Microscopy</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="TRANSTHORACIC ECHOCARDIOGRAPHY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C80404">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>TTE</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A non-invasive cardiac ultrasound performed by placing the transducer on the chest.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Transthoracic Echocardiography</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="TRICHROME STAIN" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C23012">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A microscopy staining method that utilizes two or more colored, acidic dyes of contrasting colors. Masson trichrome is a mixture of three dyes including aniline blue, Beibrich scarlet and Weigert's iron hematoxylin. Other related, modified trichrome staining methods include Lillie's trichrome, Gomori's trichrome and Mallory's trichrome.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Trichrome Staining Method</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="TRIPLE-PHASE MRI SCAN" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C130184">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A type of magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) in which images are taken during three distinct timing points (phases) following the injection of contrast material: arterial, venous, and delayed.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Triple Phase MRI</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="TRIPLE-PHASE SPIRAL CT SCAN" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C19907">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A type of computed tomography (CT) in which images are taken during three distinct timing points (phases) following the injection of contrast material: arterial, venous, and delayed.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Triple-Phase Spiral CT</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="TURBIDIMETRY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C111328">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A method to quantify the opaqueness of a liquid using a turbidimeter, by measuring the decrease in light intensity due to the scattering effect of suspended particles in the liquid sample.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Turbidimetry</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="TWO-COLOR MICROARRAY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C116153">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Dual-channel Microarray</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Two-channel Expression Array</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Two-channel Microarray</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Two-color Microarray-based Gene Expression</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A genomic microarray-based method using cDNA from two samples, labeled with two separate fluorophores/dyes at different emission wavelengths, and hybridized to a single microarray. The relative fluorescence intensity of each dye is being measured.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Two Color Microarray</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="U-HPLC/MS/MS" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C122176">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>An analytical technique where ultra-high performance liquid chromatography is coupled to tandem mass spectrometry in order to separate, identify, and quantify substances in a sample.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Ultra High-performance Liquid Chromatography/Tandem Mass Spectrometry</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ULTRASOUND" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C17230">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A technique in which high-frequency sound waves are bounced off internal organs and the echo pattern is converted into a 2 dimensional picture of the structures beneath the transducer.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Ultrasonography</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="URANYL ACETATE STAIN" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C92303">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A microscopy staining method that utilizes uranyl acetate, a water insoluble yellow crystalline solid, which is used as a negative stain in electron microscopy.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Uranyl Acetate Staining Method</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="WEBER GREEN STAIN" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C85828">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A microscopy staining method that utilizes a modified trichrome stain to determine the presence of microspordial, sporulating species. The staining method utilizes chromotrope 2R, a red acidic dye, the counterstain fast green, and phosphotungstic acid.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Weber Green Staining Method</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="WESTERN BLOT" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C16357">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A method for the detection or identification of proteins or peptides that have been separated by gel electrophoresis and transferred onto nitrocellulose or other type of paper or nylon membrane. The proteins are then detected by reaction with enzymatically labeled or radiolabeled antibody probes.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Western Blotting</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="WRIGHT STAIN" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C85829">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A microscopy staining method that utilizes the Romanowsky stains, eosin and methylene blue, solubilized in methanol. In this staining protocol, methanol is also utilized as a fixative agent prior to staining.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Wright Staining Method</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="WRIGHT-GIEMSA STAIN" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C23041">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A microscopy staining method that is a combination of the Wright and Giemsa staining protocols and utilizes the Romanowsky stains, which are mixtures of eosin and thiazine dyes such as methylene blue. It produces darker blue and magenta shades than the giemsa stain alone, which may provide better contrast in microscopy.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Wright-Giemsa Staining Method</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="X-RAY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C38101">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Static X-Ray</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A radiographic procedure using the emission of x-rays, a type of penetrating energy wave.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>X-Ray</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="X-RAY FLUORESCENCE SPECTROMETRY" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C85830">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A spectrometric method that determines the type and concentration of elements or chemicals in a sample, based upon the principle that each element emits fluorescent light of a particular wavelength when exposed to an X-ray.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>X-Ray Fluorescence Spectrometry</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ZIEHL NEELSEN ACID FAST STAIN" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C85831">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A microscopy acid fast staining method that utilizes Ziehl-Neelsen carbol fuchsin, acid alcohol and methylene blue, to determine the presence of acid fast microorganisms. This acid fast staining technique requires heating during the primary staining step involving the carbol fuchsin.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Ziehl Neelsen Acid Fast Staining Method</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <nciodm:CDISCSubmissionValue>METHOD</nciodm:CDISCSubmissionValue>
                <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Method</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                <nciodm:PreferredTerm>CDISC SDTM Method Terminology</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
            </CodeList>
            
