<CodeList xmlns="http://www.cdisc.org/ns/odm/v1.3" xmlns:nciodm="http://ncicb.nci.nih.gov/xml/odm/EVS/CDISC" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" OID="CL.C128688.MSTESTCD" Name="Microbiology Susceptibility Test Code" DataType="text" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C128688" nciodm:CodeListExtensible="Yes">
                <Description>
                    <TranslatedText xml:lang="en">Terminology relevant to the test codes that define microorganism responses to antimicrobial agents.</TranslatedText>
                </Description>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="IC50FCB" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C116250">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>IC50 Fold Change from Baseline</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A fold change based on a concentration of a specific drug expected to produce 50 percent inhibition of the standard growth of a microbial organism, or of a biological/biochemical reaction. It is a ratio calculated by the current IC50 Subject Result divided by the IC50 Subject Result from the baseline visit.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Half Maximal Inhibitory Concentration Fold Change from Baseline Measurement</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="IC50FCR" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C116249">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>IC50 Fold Change from Reference</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A fold change based on a concentration of a specific drug expected to produce 50 percent inhibition of the standard growth of a microbial organism, or of a biological/biochemical reaction. It is a ratio calculated by the IC50 Subject Result divided by the IC50 Reference Control Result.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Half Maximal Inhibitory Concentration Fold Change from Reference Measurement</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="IC50R" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C116248">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>IC50 Reference Control Result</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A reference control sample response based on a concentration of a specific drug expected to produce 50 percent inhibition of the standard growth of a microbial organism, or of a biological/biochemical reaction.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Half Maximal Inhibitory Concentration Reference Control Result Measurement</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="IC50S" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C116247">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>IC50 Subject Result</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A measurement of titer of a microbial organism or biological/biochemical reaction that has been exposed to a concentration of a specific drug expected to produce 50 percent inhibition of the standard growth of the microbial organism, or of a reaction.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Half Maximal Inhibitory Concentration Subject Result Measurement</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="IC95FCB" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C116254">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>IC95 Fold Change from Baseline</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A fold change based on a concentration of a specific drug expected to produce 95 percent inhibition of the standard growth of a microbial organism, or of a biological/biochemical reaction. It is a ratio calculated by the current IC95 Subject Result divided by the IC95 Subject Result from the baseline visit.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>95 Percent Maximal Inhibitory Concentration Fold Change from Baseline Measurement</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="IC95FCR" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C116253">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>IC95 Fold Change from Reference</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A fold change based on a concentration of a specific drug expected to produce 95 percent inhibition of the standard growth of a microbial organism, or of a biological/biochemical reaction. It is a ratio calculated by the IC95 Subject Result divided by the IC95 Reference Control Result.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>95 Percent Maximal Inhibitory Concentration Fold Change from Reference Measurement</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="IC95R" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C116252">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>IC95 Reference Control Result</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A reference control sample response based on a concentration of a specific drug expected to produce 95 percent inhibition of the standard growth of a microbial organism, or of a biological/biochemical reaction.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>95 Percent Maximal Inhibitory Concentration Reference Control Result Measurement</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="IC95S" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C116251">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>IC95 Subject Result</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A measurement of titer of a microbial organism or biological/biochemical reaction that has been exposed to a concentration of a specific drug expected to produce 95 percent inhibition of the standard growth of the microbial organism, or of a reaction.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>95 Percent Maximal Inhibitory Concentration Subject Result Measurement</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="ICNETAS" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C116255">
                    <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Inhibitory Concentration Net Assessment</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>An indication of reduced or increased susceptibility of a microbial organism, or activity of a biological/biochemical reaction in response to the inhibitory concentration (IC50 and/or IC95) of a specific drug.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Inhibitory Concentration Net Assessment Measurement</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="MIC" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C128985">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A measurement that specifies the minimum concentration of the agent at which organism growth was inhibited.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Minimum Inhibitory Concentration Test</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <EnumeratedItem CodedValue="MICROSUS" nciodm:ExtCodeID="C85540">
                    <nciodm:CDISCDefinition>A measurement of the response of the microbial organism to a controlled concentration of an antimicrobial agent.</nciodm:CDISCDefinition>
                    <nciodm:PreferredTerm>Microbial Susceptibility Test</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
                </EnumeratedItem>
                <nciodm:CDISCSubmissionValue>MSTESTCD</nciodm:CDISCSubmissionValue>
                <nciodm:CDISCSynonym>Microbiology Susceptibility Test Code</nciodm:CDISCSynonym>
                <nciodm:PreferredTerm>CDISC SDTM Microbiology Susceptibility Test Code Terminology</nciodm:PreferredTerm>
            </CodeList>
            
